them to the icsa lombard general
insurance company limited
q3 and nine month si 22 earnings
conference call
from the senior management we have with
us today mr bhargav das gupta md and ceo
of the company mr gopal balochandran cfo
and cro
mr sanchez mantri executive director
retail
and mr aloo ka garwal executive director
wholesale
please note that any statements comments
i made in today's call that may look
like forward-looking statements are
based on information presently available
to the management and do not constitute
an indication of any future performance
as future involved risk and
uncertainties which would cause results
to differ materially from the current
views being expressed
as a reminder all participant lines will
be in the lesson only mode
and there will be an opportunity for you
to ask questions after the presentation
concludes
should we need assistance during the
conference call please signal an
operator by pressing star then 0 on your
touchstone phone
i now hand the conference over to mr
bharara grass gupta md and ceo ica
lombard general insurance limited
thank you and over to you
thank you
good evening to each one of you thank
you for joining the earnings conference
call of icy lumbar general insurance
company for q3 and nine months of fy22
i hope you and your colleagues and
family members are all safe and
healthy will give you a brief overview
of the industry trends and developments
that we've witnessed in the last few
months post this rca mr gopal bala
children will share their financial
performance of the company for the
quarter and nine months ended december
2022. the data for q3 fi 22
indicates that the momentum in the
economy activity has gained further
traction aided by expanding vaccination
coverage and release of pent-up demand
contact intensive industry services and
urban demand recruit on in improving
consumer optimism
amidst this the researchers of covet 19
infections by where the omicron variant
has created some sense of uncertainty
especially for service industries while
this may have some impact on the
near-term growth given the ramp up in
the vaccination program
its overall impact on the economy is
expected to be lower than the first and
the second wave
moving to the gi industry the industry
during
fi 22 delivered mixed performance
segments such as motor insurance
business continued headwinds due to
heightened competitive intensity cheap
shortages in the four-wheeler segment
and weak festival demand in the
two-wheeler segment health insurance on
the other hand continue to show robust
growth primarily driven by group health
while growth in retail health has
moderated since q2 of this fiscal due to
base effects
as far as commercial lines are concerned
segments such as fire marine and
engineering lines witness strong growth
in sync with the current market
environment
overall the industry registered a growth
of eleven point two percent in nine
months of effect 22 and a growth of
eight percent in q3 of fi 22 as per
disclosures on the website of irdi
the combined ratio of the industry was
119.3 in h1 fi-22 as compared to 105.6
in h1 of 2021 based on available
information from public disclosures
excluding three companies
further the overall combined ratio
private multi-line general insurance was
112.4 in h1 fy 2022 as number 203.2 in
h121 excluding one
company moving to business impact this
quarter
as you know we have been making
investments to benefit from the
opportunity that the current environment
has to offer especially in the retail
health segment
these investments are
gradually steering growth for us thereby
enabling us to gain market share in our
preferred line of business
in that backdrop of the thousand uh
incremental head count to be added in
our retail health agency salesforce we
have rolled out offers for 800 and have
successfully onboarded close to 400 of
them during
this quarter
as a result we are seeing month-to-month
improvement in growth and we expect the
growth through this channel to
accelerate in the next few quarters as
the soil starts getting productive
as indicated during her earlier falls
there was a base effect on the health
benefit segment for the first three
quarters of fi 2022 from the middle of
the current quarter the base effect
started to fade as a result of which
health business from our banker channels
grew by 15 in december of 2021.
going ahead we expect this channel to
continue to deliver robust growth
our one-stop solution for all insurance
and wellness needs i'll take care app
has surprised surpassed 1.1 million
downloads with successful submission of
over 95 000 claims and over 55 000
technical teleconsultation requests
our objective is to get closer to our
customers by providing a unique digital
platform for continuous engagement to
help them take better care of their
health motor and other risks anytime
anywhere
as indicated in our previous earnings
calls in group health segment our
continuous
direct engagement with large corporates
enabled us to retain over 90 of our
customers at a higher price thereby
improving in in premium per life since
june 2021 the underlying environment
suggests that the consumers are willing
to pay a higher premium for better
coverage and adopt technology for better
customer service thus creating an
opportunity for us to grow in this
segment
in motors we continue to come combat
challenges from the lack of motor tp
rate hike for over two consecutive years
heightened competitive intensity in the
motor od segment chip shortages in the
new private car sales etc however our
expectation is that these are short-term
challenges
when we take a closer look on ground on
the private car side the consumer
sentiment remains strong
and during the quarter we continue to
focus on growing our market share in
certain key profitable sub segments
as far as the commercial lines are
concerned we have seen strong growth and
believe we are in that environment now
where the growth will continue
in current times the magic major trend
has been the significant increase in
online buying by consumers
at issa lombard we've been continuously
investing in this front our digital one
team is set up like a full stack ensure
tech firm consisting experts across
functions operating together like a
fully functional entity within the
overall organizational framework
business source through our website
increased by twenty percent and qc fi
twenty two
within this our health business grew by
twenty two point nine percent travel
business grew by hundred fifty six point
nine percent and motor business grew by
eleven point nine percent
business sourced by this
team through strategic alliance partners
in the digital ecosystem grew by seventy
percent in q3 of five twenty two
our digital one business is fully
empowered to deep mind customer data
fine-tune customer outreach efforts
service customers to claim systems that
enable real-time communication and
thereby optimize cost of acquisition we
are excited on the progress of this
channel and believe it is all set to
drive benefit and benefit from the
longer term opportunities the current
environment is offering us
overall our focus on sustainable market
leadership continued through the third
quarter as we prioritize underwriting
discipline portfolio optimization and
growing in segments that are favorable
and fall within our risk appetite
we remain on track and are focused on
growth levels such as strengthening our
distribution engine aided by lower base
effect
realizing synergy rationalizing cost
while scaling up our preferred lines of
business servicing customers with
excellence digital advance environment
advancements that will enable us to
sustain the return on equity objective
over longer term
i will now request gopal to take you
through the financial numbers for the
recently concluded quarter
good evening each one of you
i will now give you a brief overview of
the financial performance of the company
for q3 and 915.22
we have put up the results presentation
on our website you can access it as we
walk you through the performance numbers
the effects of the damage in the
financials has been incorporated in the
form of opening networks as on april 1
2021.
further the financials for the current
year represent numbers of the merged
entity
and the comparative reference for the
previous year in the financials
pertaining to standalone icc lumbar and
hence they are not comparable
gross direct premium income of the
company was at
133.11 billion rupees in nine months at
522 as against rupees 105.25 billion in
nine months by 21. the industry reported
a double digit growth of 11.2 percent on
a lower base for a similar period
our gdp growth was primarily driven by
growth in preferred segments given that
our approach has always been growing
business sustainably
the fire segment gdpi was replaced 22
billion in nine months fi 22 as again
should play seventeen point four eight
billion in nine months fi twenty one
as indicated in our results presentation
the overall gdp of our property and
casualty segment was rupees
39.34 billion in nine months five twenty
two as against thirty point six one
billion in nine months inside twenty one
on the retail side of the business gdp
of the motor segment was which is fifty
eight point one five billion nine months
five twenty two that's again should be
fifty one point four eight billion in
nine months five twenty one
to harness the potential of these
segments we have been expanding our
distribution network to increase
penetration in tile free entire four
cities
our agent including the point of sale
distribution increased to eighty one
thousand nine sixty nine times on
december 31 2021 up from 78 000.35 as on
september 30 2021.
the advanced premium was rupees 34.59
billion as that 31st december 2021 as
against
66.86 billion
as at september 30 2021
resultantly combined ratio was hundred
and eleven percent in nine months fi
twenty two as against ninety nine point
one percent in nine months fi twenty one
and hundred and fourteen point three
percent in h1 fy twenty twenty two
combined ratio was 104.5 percent in
quarter three five twenty two as against
ninety seven point nine percent in
quarter three up by twenty one and
hundred and five point three percent in
quarter to five twenty two our
investment assets grows through seventy
four point five four billion at 31
december 2021
up from rupees 371.95 billion and
september 30 2021. our investment
leverage debt of borrowings was 4.23
times at december 31 2021 compared to
4.27 times at september thirty twenty
twenty one
investment income was at rupees twenty
two point nine five billion in nine
months five twenty two that's against
between sixteen point five nine billion
in nine months five twenty one on a
quarterly basis investment income was at
risk 6.9 billion in quarter three five
twenty two as against rupees five point
six eight billion in quarter three and
five twenty one
our capital gains was at risk six point
zero one billion in nine months at five
twenty two as against rupees two point
nine two billion nine months five twenty
one
capital gains in quarter three five
twenty two was that rupees one point
three one billion
as again should be one point zero eight
billion in quarter three up by twenty
one
the expenses incurred of approximately
rupees point one six billion on account
of the de-merger has been absorbed in
the pnl during nine months fi-22
as indicated in our previous earnings
call during the integration process
we were able to smoothly transition and
on-board our partners to seamlessly
operate with minimal disruption
our branch network as at december 31
2021 stood at 285
as against 431 as at september 30 2021.
apart from the immediate benefit this
transaction entails an opportunity to
unlock significant operational and
revenue synergies and times to come
we are on the right path on our roadmap
of realizing this energy benefits by the
second half of fiscal 2023.
our profit before tax was rupees 12.73
billion in nine months five twenty two
has again should be fifteen point zero
four billion nine months at five twenty
one whereas profit before tax was four
point two one billion in quarter three
five twenty two has again shipped four
point one eight billion in quarter three
last year
consequently profit of the tax
was rupees nine point five nine billion
in nine months five twenty two as i get
11.27 billion in quarter nine months at
five twenty one
whereas profit after tax for this
quarter three stood at three point one
eight billion
as compared to
three point one four billion in quarter
three five twenty one
return on average equity was fifteen
point one percent in nine months five
twenty two s against twenty two point
four percent in nine months five twenty
one the return on average equity for
quarter three five twenty two was
fourteen point six percent as against
seventeen point six percent in quarter
three at five twenty one
solvency ratio was at 2.45 times at
december 31 2021
as against 2.49 times that september 30
2021. it continued to be higher than the
minimum regulatory requirement of 1.5
times as i conclude i would like to
reiterate we continue to stay focused on
profitable growth
sustainable value creation and
safeguarding interest of policy holders
at all times
i would like to thank you all for
attending our earnings conference call
and we would be happy to take any
questions that you may have thank you
thank you very much
we will now begin the question and
answer session
anyone who wishes to ask a question may
press star and one on the touchstone
telephone
if you wish to withdraw yourself from
the question queue you may press star
and two
participants are requested to use
answers while asking a question
ladies and gentlemen we will wait for a
moment while the question queue
assembles
[Applause]
the first question is from the line of
surname mukherjee from bnk securities
please go ahead
yeah thank you for the opportunity sir
so i have couple of questions uh first
uh on the motorcycle if you could throw
some light on the reason for the
underwriting
for this business
is it because of any kind of exchange
after amanda mentioned
or any other driver of the team
um
you know on the motor side as we've been
saying uh on the uh the underlying
challenge is more in terms of the uh
distribution aggression that we are
seeing on the ground it's not to do with
the merger on the merger front actually
we are quite happy with the way things
are progressing
um except for as we had earlier uh said
except for three or four oem uh
dealership we've in you know we've
actually got
a complete synergy in terms of
benefiting from that distribution
channel
we are also uh you know seeing growth
across most of the uh agency and the
other distribution channels that we've
uh
you know
acquired through the uh
integration the real challenge on the
ground has been
you know we've always found that
whenever the growth slows down in the
market because of you know because of
various pressure and you right now we
have challenges the market because of
chip shortage for private car because of
online demand for two wheelers so
overall the industries are growing as
fast as it is used to uh the motor
insurance industry and whenever the
substitutions happen we find that the
market as in our industry gets very
aggressive on sourcing
that's the real reason why uh the motor
book is underperforming if you look at
the largest from the cost side on the
loss ratio side it's also because of the
fact that the
case frequency is now gone back to
normal
first two quarters we have some benefits
because of relatively you know slower uh
you know utilization lower utilization
because of some knockdowns uh you know
across the country that has that went
away in q3 so the loss issues have
climbed back up to what we believe is
more
normal so those are the real reasons
that we are seeing so it's more
underlying industry issues and you know
within that our uh experience rather
than any
uh rather than the merger
okay so so uh then if i uh look ahead on
the motor side uh basically you have
commented uh that you know you had doing
some green chips in certain segments
in previous calls you had mentioned that
so what would be the trends now because
uh i think uh this kind of challenges
are continuing for quite some time
especially competitive intensity so are
you seeing situations improving and what
is what is the status in terms of you
know you have talked about price
increases also in second segment earlier
yeah what we have been saying that we
don't
expect that to happen or at least our
experience tells us that that should
happen from next year we don't expect
anything this year as we've been saying
uh there are two components on the price
increase one is the third party price
increase that is more uh tennis and
regulatory driven
again we believe that the industry needs
a direct price increase but that is as i
said you know driven by the regulator we
can't we don't control that but two
years we've not seen a price increase we
are hopeful that this year we'll see one
uh on the other side is one where we
have greater control as an industry and
as i said i think the industry benefited
a bit from the first quarter because of
uh lower usage and
that's a benefit that
people probably have factored in in
terms of their questions so
we've never we've not we've been saying
that we don't expect the price
correction this year but we are hoping
that we should see that uh you know from
next year onwards historically we've
never seen you know two to three years
of uh price aggression uh in these two
years we've seen two coveted lockdowns
that has probably been the reason why
this is sustained for this longer period
from our perspective i believe we've
kind of
you know done most of the connections
that we wanted to
and on this base we are reasonably
confident that we'll start going from
the coming quarter onwards
okay that's that's very helpful sir uh
additionally on the
user may i request to please reach on
the queue we have participants waiting
for sure
sure i'll join back thank you thank you
ladies and gentlemen in order to ensure
that the management is able to address
questions from all participants please
limit your questions to two per
participant if you have a follow-up
question you may rejoin the queue
the next question is from the line of
abhishek saraf from jefferies peace
corps
yeah
um
so it appears that this quarter we have
had the higher retention at around 76
percent versus what was there in the
previous two quarters of this year
around 66 60 and 68
so what explains this stance which
category have we seen higher retention
and is it driven by the insurer or we
are doing it on our own volition that's
the first question uh second i noticed
that our investment yield both on the
policyholder investments or shareholder
investments have actually come down
uh
quarter and quarter
while the yield curve or the rates have
generally been on an upward trajectory
so if you can just help me understand
what has happened there also it will be
very helpful thanks a lot so i'll ask
popeye to take the first one it's
largely into the mix of business
with regard to the second one
in terms of the investment yield
the aggregate yield could be driven a
little bit by the
mix of capital gains that we have
overall the book is earning roughly
about seven percent
and when interest rates go up our mark
to market benefit that we are sitting on
the bond book that goes away but equally
the uh new flow that we get into the uh
you know investment portfolio that earns
a higher letter now given the overall uh
mix of the new flow versus the old stock
the new flow impact is very little
because it takes some time for you know
you know related to the overall size of
the book which is 38 000 crore the new
flow will be much much smaller
so you don't see that impact too soon
while you see the impact of the market
market benefit of the one book going
going away but anyways one book for us
more or less has been kind of more of an
atm strategy so we don't see a problem
with that
but as the mix of the book changes with
a greater flow coming in the increased
yield uh you know starts benefiting us
only reinsurance allows mobile to answer
the question yeah i wish i could happen
here to you as well uh i think on the
retention side knows as markov said
there is no specific change in the
retention philosophy that pretty much
kind of remains the same
is just that what you see in quarter one
typically you end up seeing a lot of
corporate renewals happening
where relatively the proportion of
reinsurance is higher and retention is
to that extent slightly lower and where
i think quarter two i think if you
recollect what we have been saying a
consequent to the d merger we have also
kind of inherited the
crop book that barcelox had already kind
of committed to
and that book is something that got
booked in quarter two and which is why
you see a relatively lower retention for
quarter two quarter three is typically
the period where you actually see a
large part of the business being
underwritten on the retail retail
franchise
predominantly motor and health where in
line with what we have mentioned no
change in the retention philosophy
typically these are small ticket
policies where our
retentions are relatively higher but
otherwise at an aggregate basis no
change in our retention philosophy as
such it is purely a function of what
kind of bricks of distance that we have
underwritten in q1 and q2
sure thank gopal thanks also quite clear
uh so basically one can then
probably going forward build in that
these kind of things in the retention or
reinsurance
percentages would be broadly in line
with the mix of that particular quarter
uh just one thing if i can uh ask
on
uh covet claims for the this quarter if
you can share that data how was the how
were the net coverage claims for us this
quarter and
uh i believe that
in last quarter we mentioned that we see
some
release also so what has been the
uh uh the trend there on covet claims in
this quarter if you can just throw some
like on that
what we had talked about was for the
first half of the year
for which claims
was about 5.61 billion rupees
now that number if you look at a nine
month basis stands revised at about 5.29
so hence to that extent while
in line with what we are seeing as let's
say declining trend on the wave two
related uh covet cases
obviously in uh relative to the approach
of reserving that we are kind of built
in water one
as i said nine month number stands at
about 5.29
having said that i think what it will be
important for us to kind of watch for
which is what we will do in quarter four
is this uh
wave three impact that has started to
kind of play out obviously early trends
in terms of the number of uh cashless
intimations that we are seeing
tends to be slightly uh maybe lower than
the peak what we had seen in wave two
but having said that obviously we will
monitor the development of intimation
because these are cashless requests
honestly we have to wait for in case if
there are any reimbursement claims that
gets intimated which typically happens
that will lag
but on the wave two related uh coveting
product i think as i said nine month
number stands at about 5.29
well that's it thank you
thank you the next question is from the
line of nade strain from invested please
go ahead
uh thanks for the positive i said uh how
should we think about combined ratio and
are we going forward
given that this was a pretty normal
quarter from uh uh from a claims ratio
perspective uh and our combined ratio is
around 105 percent of water uh so uh how
should we think about combined ratio
over next uh coming year uh also we
expect some energy
so
uh should we expect this number to turn
towards hundred percent over here over
the next couple of years
uh yeah
as we've been saying uh we believe that
you know as you know the module just
the consolidation effectively happened
uh in the last month of last quarter so
we've started taking uh most of the
calls that we need to take in terms of
the synergy benefit of the cost side uh
on the revenue side as i explained we've
uh we are quite happy with the way
things are playing out in terms of
the uh synergy with the existing
distribution that uh you know that that
bharti team had already built and we are
seeing growth coming through in some of
those partnerships as well
but the entire benefit for this as we've
been saying will take some time uh and
our sense is that we will start to see
the benefit play out maybe by you know
we have been saying fi 2024 but we think
it will probably be a bit uh earlier
than that so you know the second half of
next year we will start seeing that
benefit now if you look at the combined
uh you know on a proforma basis uh the
pre uh
deal announcement and i say number three
digital announcement if you look at the
pro forma integration
that would have been about 104 combined
uh so the question is how soon can we
bring that
down now today what's the situation is
that the
core underlying business of icc robot is
also not at uh you know the 500 number
that we used to experience because of
all the pressures that we've talked
about
uh so it may be
you know challenging to bring it under
100 that we have seen in the past but
directionally it will start uh coming
down and in terms of the synergies uh
maybe gopal can explain some of his work
that has already happened
yes i think uh
i mean we have been we have been kind of
talking about broadly three areas of
synergy right i think in line with just
to kind of
refresh uh i think tax energies is
something that i mean as we fight we
will be filing the returns of 2021 by
january 31st so we will
in line with what we have said earlier
we will be able to absorb
the full benefit of the carry forward
losses
on the cost spread i think as a part of
our opening remarks which is what we
kind of put out i think we have looked
at the
overall
office infrastructure and clearly i
think we have been able to kind of uh
keeping in mind the policyholder
interest we have been able to kind of
look at what kind of
existence do we need to have in so far
as physical offices are concerned and
clearly the numbers as at the 31st
december the number of office networks
and devices 285
so again so given the fact that this
rationalization of the office
infrastructure has happened in quarter
three and more towards
the latter part of the quarter so you
will again start to see some benefit of
the synergies in the form of cost
playing through from q4 onwards
equally i think we have been kind of
looking at various areas of uh
productivity improvements and
efficiencies which is what we are kind
of indicated as an earlier call to play
out over the next six to nine months so
then again we are on course
in order to be able to realize a better
improvement in productivity when we look
at the other cost elements
the final cost element in terms of
technology related spend where again we
will be able to kind of see benefits on
synergy playing out that will take some
time because over the next 9 to 12
months is when we will be able to
significantly migrate
even let's say historical
data and other related information so
the impact of technology related spend
on this energy front will start to play
through most probably towards
the second half of the next financial
year but otherwise on course to kind of
realize most of the cost elements that
we had thought about and the revenue
synergies as barca explained
something that we will again start to
realize towards the second half of the
next financial period
sure sure and secondly across uh uh
financial service segments we keep on
hearing noises around disruption
uh we have seen significant disruption
in some of the segments like broken in
our industry also uh a lot of new age
companies are coming up uh
in terms of distribution there is a new
company coming up to the new model which
are coming up in the in the
entire manufacturing site on the general
insurance uh some of these business
models have also succeeded outside india
so how do we think about uh from a
long-term perspective uh with respect to
uh these possibility of disruption to
our business
so uh you know i think we've been
discussing this uh pretty regularly you
know if you look at the uh
the scope for disruption there are you
know both in terms of ensure tech the
way people source policies where the way
people service policies very people
service claims
there is a tremendous scope for
disruption again using uh digital tools
that are
now available
similarly there is also some amount of
disruption that is possible in the
distribution side
now if you look at what we've been doing
is that on the on the first interval
sourcing policies or servicing uh you
know policies through uh
you know modern day technology that's
been an area that we've been investing
heavily uh our
approach on the business side has been
as we you know mentioned in the opening
session
statement
uh focus was to create a carve out a
team which focuses on the digital
disruption on the
on the customer acquisition site uh and
we call it our digital one team uh where
we've kind of created a team which is uh
self-contained with you know all key
capabilities you know and with separate
uh you know location separate
philosophies in terms of
even people you know processes and that
team has been ramping up and
we are reason we are quite happy with
the way the team is growing business
both in terms of
uh tying up with uh digital uh ecosystem
partners and as i explained in this
quarter we've seen a 70 growth in that
business as also in terms of the
business that gets written on our
website and we've seen about 20 growth
in this quarter on business written on
our website
now
the other thing that we have to study is
the
the uh you know honestly speaking the
fact that some of these players are
willing to uh lose a lot of money for
growth
uh we have to be a bit more calibrated
than some of them uh obviously our
philosophy has always been to
build a sustainable model
and we may not want to go to the level
of losses that some of them incurred but
even without that we are reasonably
confident that we are able to grow we
will be able to grow the segment quite
fast towards that we are also uh you
know
you know towards this end of this
quarter we've taken a fair amount of
calls uh and we believe that that will
reflect an even faster growth in this
channel going in
on the claim side uh we've been giving
out some numbers uh you know in terms of
digital claim settlement that you've
seen both from motor and health using ai
ml etc those numbers are increasing by
the quarter even this quarter we have
significant increase in
the claims that we process through our
inspect
service as also the
cashless authorization that we give
using our ml uh feature and similarly
for us in terms of the initiative on the
ielts take care side
that's the way we believe we will be
able to engage uh with customers even
better uh on a web-based platform or a
mobile app so rather and
build
greater connect while providing the
usual insurance services and there the
focus is not just in terms of the usual
things that you know insurance companies
provide but a lot more
uh
you know services and features
which increase uh
you know engagement and potentially
reduces risk for our customers
so this is a this is a big trust area
for us though you know
in terms of the digital disruption
sorry to interrupt my request mr drain
to please rejoin the queue we have
participants reading before return
thank you
the next question is from the lion of
sri shivani from clsa please go ahead
hi thank you thank you for the
opportunity hi sir i wanted to ask you a
question if i see the uh third quarter
uh uh gross numbers for uh lombard and
including
the base so there has been a purpose and
contraction for this quarter for the
combined entity while the industry or
the private players were at around five
to eight percent now motor we can see
has regrown much more twelve thirteen
percent for the combined entities while
the private players are still going
around six percent on the health side
again uh lombard uh consolidated because
around three percent growth for third
quarter while uh the industry and the
private players are significantly higher
so if you can uh if you can give us some
understanding of uh how do you plan what
is your growth uh target it's not target
but how you plan uh your growth across
these two segments because these are
your largest segments basically and what
uh what should we expect for the uh
coming year or uh for the coming courses
uh
separately uh let me start with motor uh
so
if you look at some of the commentaries
that you've given on the motor site if
you look at the three sub
a private car
you know two-wheeler and
commercial vehicles
we are a bigger player in terms of the
private cars up segment and even a
bigger player when you look at the share
of new our share of new is much higher
than our normal share of
business as a company and at a time when
the new sales have been muted for
reasons that all of us are aware largely
to with chip shortage issues rather than
demand issue that has had a higher
impact on us than uh maybe the overall
industry
similarly if you look at our mix of
business two wheelers for us is a much
higher mix of business we are roughly
about 26 percent of our motor mix coming
from formulas industry mix will be about
roughly about 15
now two wheeler slow down has hence
affected us a bit more we you know from
a market share perspective we are fine
within the segment but from a mixed
perspective our uh you know growth gets
affected when two illness close down on
the commercial vehicle side there has
been a growth again you know while for
the industry commercial vehicle is
roughly about 40 45
for us it's about 17 now so when that
segment grows faster than uh ourselves
then the others then relatively we
underperformed having said that
there is also the pricing aggression
point that we've been making
uh and our sense is that most of the
cause that we wanted to take in terms of
correcting the portfolio has happened
and we remain uh
optimistic about growing or outgoing the
market from the coming quarters onwards
on the motor segment on the health again
this is unfortunately a bit of a basic
one because we were traditionally more
of a banker player and there was a basic
effect in terms of uh
ict events stopping to distribute uh
you know our benefit products that had
some amount of impact on our overall
business
but separate from that now we are seeing
that growth come back so as i explain if
you look at even during the quarter uh
you know my overall number is you know
rightly identified that the health
business has you know undergo uh for the
quarter but if you look at this in the
month of december we've outgrown the
market on the health detail health
indemnity business as we are adding more
uh
agents and distribution that we've
talked about and similarly with the bank
that base effect is largely paid out
later and our overall bank distribution
in in the month of december has grown uh
by over 15
uh because the base effect has not paid
out and we are uh optimistic that this
will start uh going from this quarter
onward even the bank has started uh
restarted uh you know selling uh
non-benefit but our individual products
as an attachment just started so we'll
have to wait to see the impact uh it
makes it take a bit of time uh but
overall uh i think the
base based effects headwinds are behind
us
and uh and on top of it we are investing
in terms of the retail agency
distribution that we've talked about so
all in all we are quite optimistic about
both uh from uh going going forward
uh particularly on your health business
uh your group group business is a bigger
portion of your health portfolio so is
there any target you're putting on what
kind of mix you want to maintain between
retail and group in the health portfolio
we don't we take calls based on pure you
know risk selection i mean if let's say
group health businesses
perform
poorer we will cut down on group health
business what we are very happy with is
what we've been saying for some time uh
from june onwards after the wave two we
went back to our corporate uh clients
for
price connection uh
you know obviously
from from prospective perspectives or
for the bank
and
we said we will look at 50 to 20 price
increase we are very happy to say that
for large corporates we've got an even
higher price increase on our overall
portfolio basis on our life premium
we factored in the potential uh you know
some potential third wave also in the
price and we are quite happy that we've
retained
more than 90 percent of our large
corporate accounts uh in spite of this
kind of a price increase so with this we
are reasonably confident about the
blueprint book right now
we will have to watch for the uh impact
of covet vst and the system pricing so
we don't put a target of mix we put a
target of profitability for each of the
segments
sorry to interrupt me i request myself
easily join the two mom yeah sure thank
you thank you
ladies and gentlemen uh in order to
ensure that the management is able to
address questions from all participants
please limit your question to one per
participant
if you have a follow-up question you may
rejoin the queue
the next question is from the line of
rahul shah from b capital p square
hello
happy new year to you uh my question is
uh you uh said that there were around
400 kind of uh
agents added
a retail health side but when i look at
the numbers it is some seventy from
seventy eight thousand it has gone to
eighty two thousand
so this is uh how come only four hundred
in the rate return healthy
so only ten percent is
what the 400 number is our own sales
force that we hire on our rolls
the number that you are talking about is
the agent
count so what we do is you know these
people join uh our company and then they
recruit agents
who are not on our own these are
commission agents tied agents are point
of sale agents so these are two
different numbers now when we get these
400 people as we
mentioned you know in the in the second
uh uh earnings conference call we wanted
to recruit about thousands we want to
add about thousand sales force in the in
the retail agency uh channel these are
people that will take on roles each of
them will then go on and hire
agents to do the distribution
but for our 400 of them have joined this
quarter then they will now go over
you know hire more agents and they those
agents will then produce business on the
ground
thank you
the next question is from the line of
questions
please go ahead
yeah hi happy new year everyone uh
what was the health uh
a loss ratios in the
uh in the quarter and uh even last
previous quarter we had some
uh 67 curves of
release on the health book uh so you
know like to like comparison what would
have been the uh
ratio and looking at the motor tp price
side uh where are we in the sense is iid
talking about it or
what are the processes that are needed
for the price i can has anything being
started from
higher vsa
let me take the first part uh first
pressure
on the on the first one on the health
loss ratios i think when you when you
look at the
investor tech we have put out the
numbers which includes health and
accident uh put together just on the
health side if you were to look at
what are two loss ratios for the overall
health book was seventy seven point
seven percent
water three that number stands at about
eighty two point seven percent
and if you look at quarter three last
year
uh which is for isis longboard on a
standalone basis the overall health loss
ratio stands at about 88.1
those are three numbers uh q2 77.7
q3 of current year 82.7
and q3 of last year i l on a standalone
basis at 88.1 so those are three numbers
that's in response to the first question
appears your second point on
the release of reserve that we had seen
in quarter 2 which is what i kind of
talked about
for the first half we had a net covered
impact of over 5.61 billion rupees
that's for the first half of the year
that number if you look at on a nine
month basis now stands revised at about
5.29 billion rupees
so hence to that extent i think uh
relative to the uh trend line what we
are seeing on account of wave two covet
cases i think the number stands revised
at about five point two nine
actually as i mentioned i think
obviously what we will have to wait for
is this new wave 3 that has come through
what impact does it have both in terms
of count of intimation and 2 in terms of
average claim size i think as we move
forward in this quarter i think we will
be able to give better insights
subsequently the initial trend seems to
suggest when we look at the cashless
count in terms of intimations on wave 3
relative to the peak that we had seen in
wave 2 the number of integrations under
wave 3 seems to be far lower so that's
one trend line but early early claims we
will have to wait as i said uh for more
data to come through even on the claim
size as we speak maybe it looks like
things the cases that are getting
intimidated are relatively milder and
hence to that extent maybe a 10 to 15
lower average claim size than what you
would have normally seen in a
relative portion that's what early
trends are obviously we have to wait for
for further intimations as and when we
uh get those intonations so that's one
your second point on motor third party i
think
we have been talking about the price
increase unfortunately we have not seen
a price change happening over the last
couple of years
having said that i think we have also
been talking about let's say increase in
in fact the average claim payouts
consequent to various four judgments
that we have seen over the last couple
of years
the expectation that we have is maybe as
we head into maybe fi 23
hopefully we should be able to see some
form of a draft guideline getting put
out in terms of increasing motor third
party pricing
thank you
the next question is from the line of
spark capital please go ahead
yeah thank you thank you for the
opportunity uh
we have seen a significant increase in
the optics on quarter on quarter basis
if you see the field promotional
advertisement spend has increased almost
108 percent q and q
um this is this one i want them to
understand
why why it has gone up
given given it's a combined entity um we
thought this number will will come down
uh compared to compared to what you have
done in second quarter and and and and
also just wanted to understand this
costs in every part itself
so so
if if there are low hanging source like
branch racialization and the employee
rationalization
then then what is the likely absolute
cost you could be saving during fi 23
and fi 24 so that your optics ratios uh
from martin axa uh uh uh could could
substantially improve in 23 and 24
compared to what we are seeing right now
around 35 percent is what we have sorry
30 is what we are seeing is right now
for the for the combination of
commission
so maybe some case to your first
question on the sales promotion front i
think maybe you have to always look at
the overall
expense ratios number in the context of
the mix of business that we have
i think as i kind of mentioned in one of
the responses to the earlier question q3
typically happens to the period where we
see typically bulk of the retail
distributing source
for example the mix of motor within
let's say whatever volumes of business
that we would have done is let's say q2
and q3 you will find
motor contribution contributing to a
relatively larger proportion of uh
gross newton premiums and hence to that
extent correspondingly is where you will
get to see the
cost of sourcing getting uh reflected in
so far as experience numbers are
concerned having said that i think when
you look at the aggregate
expense ratio numbers for quarter two
that number was at about 35.4 this time
talking about both operating expenses
plus commissions put together
for quarter two that number was about
35.4
that number is actually kind of slightly
uh come off and that number stands at
about 34.9 percent so hence the
detection we have actually seen
maybe a point five percent improvement
in the overall
uh management expense ratios uh in
quarter three compared to quarter two uh
so that's that's the
trend line that one would obviously want
to kind of
see as we kind of head into the
subsequent quarters
your point on let's say some of the cost
energy is getting paid out which is what
we explained your point is absolutely
right
all the office infrastructure space is
what i again responded to one of the
earlier questions if you look at
december 31 our office number stands
divided above 285 as compared to almost
more than 400 plus offices which we had
towards the end of september so we have
clearly been able to kind of get
benefits of for rationalization on the
office space a large part of it happened
towards the second half of quarter three
and hence to that extent
the impact in the form of benefits on
cost is something that you will start to
see it playing through in the q4 number
onwards
the same thing is what we would
obviously also want to see improvement
in efficiencies and productivity playing
out
even when it comes to on the physical
side again the impact of which is
something that you will see over the
next i would say six to 12 months kind
of time period the trajectory that one
would take is what i think vargo also
responded in so far as the combined
ratio is concerned again when you look
at quarter two combined we were at about
105.3
quarter three
and over the period i think you would
obviously want to try and see if you can
start seeing improvements in combined as
we head into
subsequent quarters
that's how because synergies would play
out every cost element is being looked
at and some of the
immediate benefits is something that we
already started to see and certain
elements of cost particularly aspects of
the technology side will play through
towards the second half of fi 23.
thank you
ladies and gentlemen you are requested
to please limit your question to one per
participant if you have a follow-up
question you may rejoin the queue
next question is from the line of avena
singh from mk global peace corps
hi good evening uh
two questions one firstly on that you
know your retail health claims with you
seems to be higher size in hugely
despite some 30 odd crore of uh you know
results religious uh
adjustment so while they sort of uh in
certifying due to increasing frequency
of non-coded or delayed procedures or
while there's some sort of a change on
the you know uh severity size so that's
on the retail health part
and secondly uh on the motor side uh now
we have talked a lot about competition
what uh and what was told that okay or
rarely it has happened that two three
years of intense competition but one
thing that's different in this kind of
competition
is that there are a lot of new players
like uh they have been funded or being
funded on the patterns of you know the
futuristic uh
insure tech business where sort of uh
you know the justice period or
willingness to take losses is pretty
high for longer periods and on the other
hand you have that the you know that the
large incumbents extracting to just
maintain their top line of course they
have been uh recapitalized so their
ability again to drag you know the
pricing is better uh
higher so these are two questions so how
do you see that com i mean motor only
completely easing out
well we asked great questions uh on the
first one uh it was largely because uh
elevated frequency of non-corporate
claims that we see
we've been talking about it and in q3 we
had both uh medical acute cases which is
basically the dengue malaria cases which
kind of uh
you know kind of continued from q2 uh
usually it's linked to the monsoon
season this continues in the early part
of q3
and separately on top of that the
electric surgery numbers have been uh
quite high for q3
thirdly signed in q4 both those you know
medical equity cases came down in the
second half of q3 and even electric
surgeries right now is again trending
down but we'll have to watch this trend
for uh for a period in terms of acs very
similar to the number that we gave in
the last earnings call
over a two year period we've seen
roughly about twenty percent increase so
about nine to ten percent uh annualized
increase in average game size is what we
are seeing uh which is largely a medical
inflation that we are seeing uh we will
have to again wait to see if this is
structural uh we explain the reason why
we think this is happening in terms of
uh additional tests epp suits etc uh but
you know till covet this will remain and
then you know and thereafter we'll have
to wait to see if this is structured so
that's on the health side
on the motor side you know your point is
absolutely valid uh in the past we've
not seen a
kind of a pe-funded entity which is just
going for growth
we've had disciplined uh you know
insurers who've come into the market
so that risk is there having said that
we uh
we believe that um
from our perspective we've taken the
necessary calls that we wanted to uh
this year and we are reasonably
confident that on this base will
continue to grow
on the motor book
i'm hoping that there will be some price
collection next year because of tp etc
but even otherwise we kind of geared up
to handle the sector
we've done a lot of granular analysis
doing this year to prepare ourselves for
a situation where
you know this market continues to remain
aggressive uh and we will still be able
to compete with ourselves
thank you
the next question is from the line akash
kataria from money portfolio managers
peace corps
yeah but thanks for the opportunity
you know bhargava you mentioned about
you know the app downloads 1.1 million
so you know are we happy with this
number and can you share some customer
experiences because you know
the app has certain very good features
like a consultation or a diet planning
so you know how is the customer
experience been because you know some of
these things once you know
they are appreciated and kick in
automatically you know stickiness and
cross cell can improve for us and you
know dental insurance there was some tie
up so is it you know under the same
policy are you know some of these uh
initiatives for creating a more
differentiation at our retail level kind
of
focus which is absolutely absolutely
correct you know this is exactly our
thought process on the uh on the benefit
of the app from a longer term
perspective if you look at the number
1.1 billion is just scratching the
surface
we launched this app
about two years back
largely focused on the
business to employ segment which is
basically the group and segment for
uh you know employees of our corporates
at that point in time our thought
process was this was a segment where
with whom we had hardly any engagement
uh individuals in in corporates wouldn't
even realize that the insurance was from
uh isis but unless they had a claim
and you know a small percentage of
people actually claim so the whole
process was to build engagement and then
very rapidly we realized that we needed
to pivot and provide uh you know a
comprehensive uh you know solution
across product lines to these uh uh
these customers because the same
customer was an employee of a corporate
is also a retail uh you know insurance
customer of ours uh through maybe a
motor or some other policy so we've been
consistently pivoting and you know or
we've been we've been consistently
building features on agile mode every 15
days we launched new new features on
that app and the number of downloads
that we see is really a two-year story
right now we are adding almost 100 000
uh you know new uh app users every month
on the service and the engagement we are
watching it like a hawk uh there is uh
you know we believe
you're actually right we believe this
will create stickiness and improve
processing
we launched uh the renewal and the
crosstal uh you know upsell module uh in
the middle of this year uh around june
or july or august if i recollect and
month on month we are seeing contraction
in terms of
people using the app for
uh upselling or cross-cross selling but
on a very small way so the numbers are
not meaningful in the overall scheme of
things but the growth numbers are
quite phenomenal uh we'll wait for some
time before the numbers become
meaningful to talk about some of these
is my guess but overall we are very
clear that this is going to be a
tool to you know build a strong
engagement with our customers which will
in the long term help us with
across the lobster you know and we
believe even
thank you
ladies and gentlemen this was the last
question for today i would now like to
hand the conference over to mr bharara
does gupta
you know again thank you everyone for
joining this call uh you know we are
available for
answering any other call separately feel
free to reach out in case you had a
question then time didn't permit us to
answer those then uh and look forward to
engaging you during the quarter and
thereafter thank you and take care bye
thank you so much
thank you
on behalf of ica lumbar general
insurance that concludes this conference
thank you for joining us and you may now
disconnect your lines
you